Goodsword, everyone.
Thank you to be here.
So, today we're going to talk
of flit.
We have wanted to talk
in a manner a little ludic,
a little
to play with the mo.
And the idea is
that like in Space Invaders,
we have always
well played and combats
of the enemies
and defend our planet
of this enemy.
In the life of
every day,
in the engineer of the
data or an expert elastique,
we have not
combat
but we have
to combat
a vague
of data,
so
the log,
of metric,
and we
have to collect
do all
to do
do have to
do
our
planet,
I'm
rather our
cluster.
Claster.
Before
to
start,
a little
presentation,
I'm
Pietro,
an engineer
of the
judicial
and with me
my
colleague Benjamin
DeVisa
who is
Esper
Search and
Elastic.
and developer
Java.
And
some more
on our
box,
so Adline,
it's Adline,
it's a
box based
on
Paris, we
are expert in
the domain
of search.
We are
integrator
of Elastic
Search,
OpenSearch,
and Solar.
We have
also
of the
offers of
formation,
we're
consultants
on the
three
products,
so the
Elasticse Search,
and Solar,
And we're
here editor of A2,
that's a stack
for the e-commerce.
Also,
HaldotSight,
which is a
motor of
research collaborative,
permits
to concentrate different
sources of
data
in
in the
company,
and that
will
you
make to
get
a
more
with
with a
only
only point
of
unique.
So,
so
you
know,
the
beauty of
telemetry
is to
all
collected.
.
So,
we
want
collect
del
logs,
of the
metrics and also
the lap time.
So we had
the
before the
arrival of
the fleet,
we
had
we have
you can
you
for
for collect
the log,
we
have
of file bit,
for the
for the metrics,
we had
of metric
and for
for
verify the
the
different
services,
we had
been
to install
an
Earthbit.
So you
have the
three
vessels or
the
avion,
I don't
So it was a bit for
for
each
caduce
it was an
arsenal
that was
quite
was quite
but
in the
time
it was
fragmented.
And this
fragmentation
it could
probably cause
a
problemat
because
imagine when
we
have
seen that we
a cluster
with
a
centen
or even
a million
of a million
machines.
But there
there
had
for
each machine
a bit
different.
For
in our
case of
usage.
So, if we
would
monitor
of the log,
we
have installed a
logbit.
And so we
would
do that
on
all the
entire
of the
machine.
And the
complexity
came
at
the
using of the
feature of
configuration,
because for
configuring the
different
bits,
we
had
used
to
use
using the
Fichie
IML.
So for
for
each
service
we
had
we had
different.
And the
the
problematic,
great
is not
really
in
so the
installation,
but it
also the
mis-a-ad
-a-ad-a-a-gure
how we
will
manage and how
we
will
gestire the
and how we
all of the
bits
that
monitor the
different
machines.
And so
it's a
business
a
gas
and it's
game
over.
But,
well,
we're
here today
we're here
we're there to
talk
of bits,
it's
for you
to
you know that
that
is
that nothing is
because
since
for
more at
on five
we have
had
new
solution
that was
introduced
by
elastic
it's a
solution
that
will
not
replace
the
bit,
but
that
offers an
alternative
and
an
approach a
different
so
an approach
a
pretty
unified of
observability.
We have
no
need
of three
components
distant,
we can
use
a
only
use
a
like
just
for
just to
with
the
world
of the
space invaders.
as fleet,
it's an
sort of ab
centralized, we
have
wanted to represent
flit,
like a
space
of a
vessel
mer,
in
which we
can deploy the
different
agents,
so the
little
the little
avion there
back.
So,
from
fleet.
So the
role in,
the roll-outout,
the
mis-a-
of the
agency of
the agents,
it's
so it's
very simple,
we'll have
on
an interface
an interface in
where we
can
basically
all
so
So with that
it's
facilite
not much
the
presence
of
the
use
a
we'll
see
after
why,
we have
also
we
configured
at
a
fleet server
to
make
communicate
the
solution
with
the
different
agents.
So,
like
say,
it's
very
important
the fleet,
but it's
also
important,
the
agents.
The agents
are
going
an environment
environment
virtual
that will
will be
on
chas
cost.
So the
super
power
of these
agents
is
that they're
to
monitor
they're
able to
monitor
on the
machine
on the machine
the machine on
they're
the
metrics,
and the
different
of the different
service,
of all the
services, of
a
other
thing
to
say to
say, is that
the
agents
can
also can
also of the
security.
So
they can detect
these
conduct
of the
conductors
of
detections,
the
things that
we could
have
it's
more complicated
to
do that
and it's
a
solution
that's a
pretty
possible, but
but how
how
we can
monitor
various
services,
we do
in
integrating
to
these agents
of
these agents,
we
we integrate,
as
we have
in a
manner metaphoric
for
a bit
for a
We
add
these arms.
These arms are
just
used that the
agent will use that the
to be used to
use for
for
different
services.
We have
more at
more 400 integrations
which are
compliant with
the
Elastic
as Chima
and the
thing
very
simple is that
these
integrations
come with
also
various
resources.
So it's
these resources
that can
be used
like
for example
of the
pipelines,
dashboards
that
can
need for
for, for
recuperate the
data
to
many
different sources of
for the
visualize,
like in the
case of
the dashboard.
The integrations,
we have a
for all the
SOS,
like I
have a
plus of
four hundred
integrations,
but we
have
integrations
of
the type search
for the
type for the
part security
and the
integrations for
the part
observability.
So you have
the page
on Kibana
in
that you
can
regard
the
ensemble
of the
integrations
and so how
we
will define
and how we
will
indicate to
the agent
which is
how we
use, and how
we're using,
so in
a manner metaphoric,
it's what
the instructions
for
construct for
our
avion,
with the
different
arms,
we have
just
the police
now it
we have
have
seen
the policy like
of
pretty
because we can
use
a
only policy
for
indicate
that's
the integration
different
agents
do you
do
mean that
if
if you
need
for example
change
to
make
to make
a year
times,
it's
pretty
easy,
it's pretty
we can
have
other
policies
that's
on the
same
so
the same
limit
for the
And so
I
pass the
hand
to
be
again
in
more
how I
I'm
I
knew
when it was
to
when it was to
it was about
to
talk about the
the
architecture
how it
will
be
we're
going to
all the
interface
graphics,
which
will be
made
in place
for the
administration
at
the
server
fleet and
of the
agents
and the
policeisisis
the
cluster
Elasticsesesearch
will
be there
for
collect
the
data and
the fleet
server
to coordinate
the server
and
the
right
and the
agent.
The
thing interesting
with that is
that is that the
fleet server
is there
is just for
there can
for
they're in
they're
always
they're always
they're
not
it's not
will centralize
the
collect
data
the
agent will
dialogue directly
with
the cluster
and
the
stick search
so
even if
the fleet
server
don't
we have
not
no
per
of exploitation
that's
pretty
interesting
the
fleet server
is just
there
a
problem
we can
take
the
time to
they're
We're not
we're not
we're not going to get
our
So that's the point that's
really that I'm
in Flit,
is that we're
this decouplemableable
of
the responsibility
that's
and our
cluster is
there to
always
assure
his role
of
ingestion
and it's
he's
also
stocked
in
terms of
elements.
How how
is
a process
of
enrolement?
The process of
the
the first
to
create a
policy.
So there
there
a
view a
bit
proactive
of what we
we're going to go
that
we're going to
explore the different
different types of
and we're
the different types of
machines that
are they're
they're able to
the elements that
are able to
these machines,
it's
that are
that on
a
same
policy,
we can
have the
monitoring
system,
we can
have a
monitoring
oracle,
we can
have a
monitoring
Apache,
Kafka, etc.
so you
know
what we
will make
in
our
policy,
it's in the policy,
it's in the policy
that we're parametry,
if we're
we're parametry, if we
have a
a
research of
file of
log,
it's
that we
will
define the
and
the
file of
code.
So the
contraind
is that
that you
need
that on
the
machine that
same,
we
know that
we can
on
specify
many.
But
there
we can
create
on
the
machines
type.
then
once that
we have
that,
we
will
generate a
token
of
over
via Kibana
And in Kibana, we will
will be
with a little
thing
is your
your mode of installation,
is what is your
Windows,
is it
the Linux,
or is it
the Mac?
We choose the
the architecture
processor of the
RM,
the X86.
It we generate the
all the
commands to
pass, we
pass on
the machine
where
the agent,
and in
the three minutes
you have
the
data
that comes
to arrive in
the cluster.
It's the
three,
four, and
five,
it's to
get the
the commands
proposed
will
telecharged,
enroll the agent
and then
attend
the
data
that arrive
relatively rapidly
rapidly.
The integrations
are stocked
on a
repository
which is
managed
by elastick,
which is
accessible
in line, but
we have
often
many times,
often of
clients who
function in
an
environment
that's
their
architecture
has not
access to
the world
exterior.
So how
do in
this case
that
for
power
with the
integrations
that are
able to
a repository
exterior,
repository exterior.
So,
the
The solution
the solution
thing is recommended by
Elastix is
to use
an proxy.
It's
a year that
just the
fleet
server
will access
to the internet
via a
proxy and he
will be
the
repository.
If really
it's not
possible,
we can
aber the
registry
in local,
it's an
image
docker
that we can
be telechar
but it
that means
to be
to
get to
make to
year
regularly
for
to have
all the
new
versions
of
all
And then we have two types of
we have two types of registra,
we have the EPR and the
and the
air, he will be
the
the entire of the
whole of
server
HTTP,
it's
he will get
the
elements that we
interest.
An agent
can
also be presented
in standalone,
that
once that
we've
installed and
configured,
he
will have
no
communication with
the server
server Flit.
He will continue
to
live his
all
and there
we're
the interest
major
of Flit
which is
of
can
it's
because when
when we
will create
our
server
our agent
standalone,
we'll
say it is
standalone and when
we're
attach the
police
the
place to
server
fleet he
he
will generate
a
file
yamel
that
will be
passed
in
parameters
that
will
contain
all the
elements
and
then
then then
made
so on
so if we
want
if we
the
elements of
the element of
elestestestic
for
ymelel
which is
on
each
machine,
so we
can
we're
the
server
flit,
and a
second
point
important,
is that
the
is that the
main
is
manual is
and that
the
view
on
a
little
on the
archive
on an
archive,
we
have
an
agent,
we
have
the
choice,
if
we're
on
a
machine
Linux,
install
an
RPM
or a
deb
or an
archive.
It's
installed by
an archive,
it's always
the version
we're
by the
by the package
it's
easy, it's
easy,
we're
we're doing,
installation
and it's
the
problem is that
if we
use the
package
we can
make
a
new
automatic
of the
agent,
which
is
not possible
if we
are
installed
via a
package
so it
it's
the
archives
we're
always
this
possibility
possibility of
the
it's
a parted, you know,
when we have
stories of
in Flit,
we're
have two
different,
we're having two types of
different.
We have the
the agent, which
the
version will
see the
the stack
elastic, and
we have
the
integrations who
have their
proper
cycle of
their
proper cycle of
version.
It's
two
different and
relatively
independent.
So,
it's
think to
make the
major
regularly,
but also
on the
agents
and
on the
integration,
it's not the
same
things.
What is
what we have
as an
We have
a lot of
the
box,
we've said,
there's
more
that
are
they're
with
the pipeline
and
the
index templates.
The
index templates are
useful
if you
know
if you know
too
even
it's
you can
you
your
index,
how they
are
defined,
the
type of
chants,
the
how you have
general,
the
cycle of
the cycle of
are associated.
All that will
that will be
with the
integration and
certainly the
pipeline
who will
will be
to transform
the
flow of
data in
a structure
that's
easily exploitable
for the
integration
specific.
we've been to
make in
place.
A page,
it's not
the same
thing than a
collection
of
DNS.
The formats
are
different.
By
once they
are
passed by
the Ingest
Pipeline,
we will
get used a
form
common,
of the
non of
chan common
that are
will conform
to the
CS.
We'll
find the dashboards
also, it's
quite quite
because I can't
the, I can't
people who
come to
make in place
the elastic
search,
they galare
always when
they're
at the
table of
dashboards.
It's the
moment
when they say,
how I
do that,
and
they're
pass three
years
on YouTube
to
try to
we're trying to
have
many
you have
some
an
little
alert on
the dashboard
is that
that you can
not modify
a dashboard
delivered by an
integration
because he
will be
it's
because it will be
the
new
new year
we're
we can
do it
for
adaptate,
but in
that you
have
not the
newvotet.
We have
there are
elements of
security
and
observability
that are
in the
in the elements.
As
the elements.
said
all
the
limit,
which
I'm
often
by
the client,
but if
I
want
there
policy on
my
agent
Typically, I have
the base
Oracle, I want monitor
the metrics
on the base
Oracle, but I
have certain
are certain who are
on
these machines Windows
and other
on the machines
Linux.
So I can
not make a policy
Linux, a policy
Windows,
a policy
Oracle, and
they make
on the
agents
of this
manner
there.
So there
there will
have
have been a
policy
Linux
oracle,
a policy
Windows Oracle
and in
function
of the
agents,
we're
attach to
the
one
after
I'm
in saying that it would
would be
it would be
good to make
it would be in
a year,
maybe a
I'm sure,
it's
we're also,
the custom
integrations
which are
not
many,
the custom
logs,
that
if you
have
a
format of
the
log
proprietary,
we can
can
can't
a
it's
that
you can
make
a
process of
you can
have
create
these
ingest pipelines
personalize,
so
the
ingest pipelines,
it can be
fastidue
to
have
there
a format
of log in
and he will be able to
say,
I've detected that there
we've got
a
chance and there
will propose an Ingers
Pipeline.
So we have a
cut of
this thing that
that can't
to go
and to
not be
to
conton
those elements
out of the
box.
A
migration
an agent,
that's
new,
it's
happened
recently and
it's
pretty
interesting,
is to
that
now
we have
the
possibility
if
we will create
a new cluster
because
we want
change
of architecture
we'll
do this
sort of
things,
make a
lot of
version
a lot of
sometimes
people,
when they
make
these
ones,
they prefer
create a
new
new cluster in
new and
migrate the
data,
but
we can
have
been
to migrate the
and
and so
now
there
there's
this
migration
so, that
that is
that
in the
server fleet,
we
say,
I want
move
migrate
my
and he
will
give us
all the
command to pass
for
that they
are all
they're
to get to
the
new
new cluster.
and there
it's
really
and
they're
in
re-enrolled,
it's
kind of
and we're
the police
and the
thing of
things.
The
little
the collect
of telemetry
evolved,
there,
there's
the open telemetry
that
is supported
again by
by fleet,
we have
a hotel
collector
that is
proposed,
so it
you
also
function with
things standard
if you have
the open telemetry
directly in your
applications,
which is the
way the
way to the
the way to get it.
It will
you can't
you're
to centralize
all via a
interface
which Banna, you
have the
hand on your
machines, and for
all the
house, I
have
mounted a cluster
elastic
and I
have made
these elastic
on the
on the PC
of my
times
that I'm
like
see how my
can't
see
too long
on Steam.
It's
much.
but we
can
also with
this
kind of
because because
that's
something
which is
part of
the
license
basic,
this element
that
And we
can
be
there
after
a
little
more
easy,
and it
can
function
also
of
the
cloud
of
the
Pram
and
the
so
there's
no
reason
of
we're
instructive.